好的，我们有计算冰雹序列的代码
OK, so we've got our code that computes a hailstone sequence
并将其放入列表中。
and puts it into a list.
现在为了使它成为一个完整的Java程序
Now in order to make this a full Java program there's a few more
我们需要补充的东西。
things we need to add.
因为每一句话，所有这些话
Because every statement, all these statements
需要在方法声明中，
need to be inside a method declaration,
每个方法都需要在某个类中。
and every method needs to be in some class.
所以这是最简单的方法
So this is the simplest way that we can
写我们的冰雹计划。
write our hailstone program.
我们接受这个密码。
We take this code.
我们把它包在一个方法里。
We wrap it inside a method.
下面是这种方法的外观。
And here's how the outside of that method looks.
所以这是一种叫做冰雹序列的方法。
So it's a method named Hailstone Sequence.
接受一个必须具有声明类型的参数。
Takes one argument that has to have a declared type.
在这种情况下，我们开始的是整数n
In this case, it's the integer n that we're starting
冰雹序列。
the hailstone sequence with.
它必须有一个声明的返回类型。
And it has to have a declared return type.
在本例中，是整数列表
In this case, it's the list of integers that
是冰雹序列吗。
is that hailstone sequence.
我一会儿再谈这两个关键词。
And I'll talk about these two key words in a moment.
但是函数还需要返回一些
But then the function also needs to return something
这与报税表相符
that's compatible with that return
类型，它有正确的类型。
type, that has the right type.
所以我们将返回我们创建的列表。
So we're going to return this list that we've created.
然后这个方法需要在一个类中。
And then that method needs to be inside a class.
我们叫我们班冰雹。
And we're calling our class hailstone.
这就是我们申报的方式。
And this is how we declare it.
我们把所有东西都放在大括号里
We put everything in curly braces
为了展示街区。
in order to show the blocks.
现在这里有什么新鲜事？
Now what are some of the new things here?
公开一个类和方法
So public with a class and in the method
意味着程序中的任何代码
means that any code anywhere in the program
允许引用此方法或此类。
is allowed to refer to this method or this class.
我们将看到其他一些访问修饰符，如private
We're going to see some other access modifiers like private
我们可以用它来保证程序的安全性
that we can use to get more safety in a program
在我们需要的时候保证不变性
and to guarantee immutability when we want
编写不可变类型。
to write an immutable type.
但我们将在接下来的阅读中讨论更多。
But we'll talk about that more in upcoming readings.
其他的新东西，静态的，意味着
Other new thing here, static, means
这个方法，冰雹序列方法，
that this method, this hailstone sequence method,
不会被调用对象，不会
doesn't get called on an object, doesn't
需要有一个自参数。
need to have a self-parameter.
顺便说一下，self是Java中Python中的单词。
By the way self is the word in Python in Java.
这叫这个。
This is called this.
因此不能对对象调用静态方法。
So static methods can't be called on an object.
例如，与列表相比，
Contrast that with the list, for example,
这里的list add方法。
the list add method here.
我们调用的是一个列表的特定值。
Which we're calling on a particular value of a list.
当我们调用冰雹序列时，
When we'd call a hailstone sequence,
我们不会以任何特定的价值来衡量
we wouldn't call it on any particular value
冰雹级的。
of the hailstone class.
我们不会制造一个新的价值冰雹类。
We wouldn't make a new value hailstone class.
我们会用类名来表示
We would just use the class name to say
我们得去看冰雹课
we need to go and look in the hailstone class
找到冰雹序列的方法。
and find the hailstone sequence method inside there.
事实上如果这段代码是
In fact if this code were written
在冰雹层里，我们甚至
inside this hailstone class, we wouldn't even
需要提到类本身。
need to mention the class itself.
因为我们早就到了。
Because we'd already be there.
它就可以搜索冰雹序列
It would just be able to search for hailstone sequence
在我们现在所在的班级里。
within the class we're currently in.
还有一件事我想指出
Another thing I want to point out here
这个注释在方法之前吗。
is this comment right before the method.
因为这很重要。
Because this is very important.
这个评论就是这个方法的规范，
This comment is the specification of that method,
描述输入和输出
describes the inputs and the output
在某种程度上，一个人在看这个代码
in ways that a human being looking at this code
很容易理解。
can easily understand.
所以他们不必研究代码本身
So they don't have to study the code itself
为了弄清楚这到底是怎么回事。
in order to figure out what this actually does.
但也有一些限制，
But also providing some constraints,
一些假设，代码本身没有显示。
some assumptions, that the code itself does not show.
所以这实际上需要冰雹序列
So this actually requires, the hailstone sequence
要求我们从正整数开始。
requires that we're starting with a positive integer.
因为如果我们不从一个正整数开始
Because if we don't start with a positive integer actually
坏事会发生。
bad things can happen.
我们可以永远跑下去。
And we can definitely run forever.
所以这个注释被称为规范。
So this comment is called the specification.
我们将在以后的课上更多地讨论这个问题。
We're going to talk a lot more about that in future classes.